

# Sumesh Parkar

6 Years Exp

#### **About Me**

Experienced and self-motivated Sales Manager with Six years of industry experience overseeing sales figures and new account developments. Bringing forth a proven track record of working collaboratively with sales teams to achieve goals, escalate revenue gains, and advance the sales cycle of the company. A strong leader with the ability to increase sales and develop strategies to retain customers.

## **Professional Experience**

#### FreLance Global Projects - Sales (B2B)

2022 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Present, promote and sell products/services using solid arguments to existing and prospective customers.
- Perform cost-benefit and needs analysis of existing/potential customers to meet their needs
- Establish, develop and maintain positive business and customer relationships
- Supply management with reports on customer needs, problems, interests, competitive activities, and potential for new products and services.

## Skill Lync - Inside Sales Specialist (Team Leader) 2022 - 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Collating and maintaining client information in the CRM database
- Make calls to clients and respond to callback requests
- Email & WhatsApp conversations with potential leads
- Convert potential leads into customers
- · Help Customer until they get there onboarding sessions

#### SS Enterprise - B2B Sales

2020 - 2022

Key responsibilities:

- · Generating Leads
- Understanding Requirements and the Budget
- Analyzing the location
- Preparing the estimation
- Onboarding Clients

### **My Contact**

Sumesh.parkar007@gmail.com

+91 8291659102

Mumbai, India

#### **Hard Skill**

- Strategy development
- Strong Closer techniques
- Maintaining great relations with existing clients
- Problem-solving skills
- Generating leads

#### **Soft Skill**

- Observation
- Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking

## **Education Background**

- IBSAR,Navi Mumbai
  Bachlor in Business Adminstrative
  Completed in 2016
- S.H.Jhondhale, Mumbai
  HSC
  Completed in 2013
- Model English High School SSCCompleted in 2011

#### Internship - Emirates Logistics

Helped Emirates in getting few logistic projects, visited almost 50 industries and did serve for Emirates logistics Completed my project on B2B Sales

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate of participation Institute of company secretary of India,
- Appreciation certificate Institute of Business studies and research,
- Best volunteer Certificate Institute of Business studies and research,
- Winning the M-biz (Business Event) Institute of Business studies and research.

#### HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Riding
- · Listening to Music
- Travelling
- · Connecting to new people

#### **DHFL - Management Trainee**

2018 - 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Leads Generations Strategy for the team
- Assigning Leads to the Team
- Handling objection of the clients
- Helping Team members for the closure
- · Training to the team member to improve sales

#### Kotak Mahindra Bank - Assistant Manager

2016 - 2017

Key responsibilities:

- Handling Social media escalations
- Connecting Clints through Email & Calls
- Handling Critical leads
- Selling Banking Products
- Working on Customers Feedback

#### **CAREER ASPIRATION**

Seeking a challenging position in a reputed organization where I can learn new skills, expand my knowledge, and leverage my learnings.